

Location: New York City
Telephone: +1 (347) 498-5369
Email: simon@hypertexthero.com
Portfolio: hypertexthero.com/work
Photographs: simongriffee.com/stories

Summary

I enjoy learning and absorbing information from different fields to help solve problems, keep my brain whirring and, with any luck, pass on knowledge to future generations.

With over a decade of professional graphic and web design experience while travelling extensively around the world and living in Brazil, Tunisia, Italy, England and the United States I have learned to speak and write in: **English** and **Portuguese** fluently, **Italian** well, **French** and **Spanish** in a somewhat amusing way. Using these together with **visual** and **programming languages** I have managed to:

- Increase funding for and cooperation between international organizations.
- Save people time and make them happier when using computers.
- Help groups and individuals with hands-on design, coding, editing, brainstorming and critique.

I'm based in and ♥ New York City.

Experience

Information Systems Officer (Designer & Developer)

Food and Agriculture Organization, United Nations, Rome, Italy, June 2009–Present: Helped increase funding and the number of contracting parties to the International Plant Protection Convention and raise public awareness of its work while making people using computers there happier. Hands-on design and coding work from wireframes to production of websites and print media. Organized photo groups, food and wine tasting on Fridays.

Freelance Web & Graphic Designer · Hypertexthero, Worldwide, 2005–Present: Completed a variety of web and print projects for clients around the world, from large companies in London and internet startups in the Bay Area to non-profits and United Nations agencies in Rome.

Web & Graphic Designer · *Acotel Group S.p.A, Rome, Italy, 2003–2004:*Created the first web standards based website design project in Italy.
Completed identity design projects, marketing and advertising multimedia campaigns.

Freelance Web & Graphic Designer

European Artisans, Various, Rome, Italy, 1999–2003: Freelance designer for an internet startup and various clients.

Education

I learned to work with computers with computer games. I learned graphic design from books, interfaces, posters and films by designers like Milton Glaser, Susan Kare, Robert Bringhurst and Saul Bass. I learned HTML and CSS by viewing the source of websites, searching with Google and reading Zeldman's Designing With Web Standards. I learned user experience, usability and accessibility principles from The Cluetrain Manifesto, Don't Make Me Think and Jacob Nielsen's Alertbox column. I learned photography by taking and looking at photographs. I learned to cook and to eat in Italy. I've been learning some Python and enjoyed meeting Alex Martelli in Florence in 2013.

Magnum Photos Workshops · Cortona 2011, Wolverhampton 2012, Paris 2013
Per Volquartz Workshop · Joshua Tree, California 2007
Stanford University, 2006 · Concept Design Workshop at Stanford University's d.school Bournemouth University, 1996–1999 · B.A. with Honours in Creative Advertising
Arts University Bournemouth, 1997–1998 · City & Guilds Diploma with Distinction in Photography

Skills & Tools

Web development: Wireframing in HTML & CSS client-side code that usually ends up in production. Some JavaScript and Python.

User experience design, usability, accessibility: Fast, simple interfaces and good writing over excessive style.

Photography: Candid photography, usually on the street using Leica rangefinder cameras and Fuji and Ricoh compacts. I want a better, more affordable camera for photography students and better editing software.

Software: Web browsers (Firefox and Chrome) and their developer tools, Textmate and a Terminal prompt, Sketch, Lightroom, Photoshop, Illustrator and InDesign. I have experience with Python and Django that I also use to edit hypertexthero.com on a local development server that is then published with rsync and version controlled with Git and GitHub. I also know a bit of Ruby and Jekyll, some Apache and Nginx configuration, a tiny bit of MySQL, PostgreSQL and SQLite, and a little Unix system administration.

Interests

Communication, information, photography, travel, independent web, open source & open internet, philosophy, typography, art history, nature, astronomy, music, (blues guitar, jazz, classical), computer simulations, vintage aeroplanes, basketball €